Dung D. Le

80 Stamford Road, School of Information Systems, Singapore Management University, Singapore 178902 **Contact:** • ddle@smu.edu.sg • (+65) 9422-8953 • https://andrew-dungle.github.io

ABOUT ME

Dung D. Le is currently a research scientist in School of Information Systems, Singapore Management University (SMU). He earned his PhD in Data Science and Engineering from the same university, working with Associate Professor Hady W. Lauw. In his candidature, he has been recognized with SMU Presidential Doctoral Fellowship Award (AY2018 and AY2019) and SMU PhD Student Life Award (AY2018 and AY2019). Formerly, he earned his Degree of Engineer in Mathematics and Informatics from Hanoi University of Science and Technology, in 2014. His research interests are in recommender systems, information retrieval, and visual analytics, with publications in major data mining and AI conferences such as AAAI, IJCAI, CIKM, and SDM.

More information about him can be found at: https://sites.google.com/view/duydungle.

RESEARCH INTEREST

My research interest includes *recommender systems*, *information retrieval*, and *visual analytics*. Specifically, my research works have been focusing on designing algorithms for analyzing user-generated data, understanding user preferences from the data, and applying the learnt knowledge to create user-centric applications.

EDUCATION

School of Information Systems, Singapore Management University,

80 Stamford Road, Singapore 178902.

PhD candidate in Data Science and Engineering

Aug 2015 – Sep 2019

- Research topics: Representation Learning, Recommendation Systems, Information Retrieval.
- · Advisor: Hady W. Lauw.

School of Applied Mathematics and Informatics, **Hanoi University of Science and Technology**, Hanoi, Vietnam.

Degree of Engineer in Mathematics and Informatics

(5-year advanced undergraduate program).

Sep 2009 - May 2014

Sep 2006 – Jun 2009

• Valecdictorian of School of Applied Mathematics and Informatics.

Mathematics class, Vinh Phuc Gifted high school,

Vinh Phuc, Vietnam.

PUBLICATIONS

CONFERENCE PAPERS

- 1. Dung D. Le, Hady W. Lauw, *Stochastically Robust Personalized Ranking for LSH Recommendation Retrieval*, AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI'20), Feb 2020.
- 2. Dung D. Le, Hady W. Lauw, *Learning Multiple Maps from Conditional Ordinal Triplets*, International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI'19), full paper, Aug 2019.
- 3. Dung D. Le, Hady W. Lauw, *Multiperspective Graph-Theoretic Similarity Measure*, ACM Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM'18), full paper, Oct 2018.
- 4. Dung D. Le, Hady W. Lauw, *Indexable Bayesian Personalized Ranking for Efficient Top-k Recommendations*, ACM Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM'17), full paper, Nov 2017.
- 5. Dung D. Le, Hady W. Lauw, *Euclidean Co-Embedding of Ordinal Data for Multi-Type Visualization*, SIAM International Conference on Data Mining (SDM'16), full paper, May 2016.

TUTORIAL

1. Dung D. Le, Hady W. Lauw, *Recent Advances on Scalable Retrieval of Personalized Recommendations*, the Thirty-Third AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI-19), January 27 – February 1, 2019.

AWARDS & SCHOLARSHIPS

- Conference Travel Awards: IJCAI 2019, AAAI 2019, CIKM 2018, CIKM 2017, SDM 2016.
- Winner of SMU Presidential Doctoral Fellowship Award AY2018 and AY2019.
- Recipient of SMU PhD Student Life Award, AY2018 and AY2019.
- Postgraduate scholarship, Singapore Management University (Aug 2015).
- Honoured as the valedictorian of School of Applied Mathematics and Informatics, Hanoi University of Science and Technology (Sep 2014).
- Scholarships of Vietnam National Program for the Development of Mathematics AY13-14, AY12-13.
- Lawrence S.Ting scholarship for excellent student AY2011-12.
- Honoured as excellent student of AY2011-12.
- National Mathematics Competition for University Students (first prize 2010, second prize 2011).
- Third prize, Vietnam Mathematics Olympiad (Mar 2009 high school level).

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Living Analytics Research Centre, School of Information Systems, **Singapore Management University**,

Position: Research Assistant

Oct 2014 – Jun 2015

- **Project**: Dimensionality Reduction for Recommendation Systems.
- Description: Construct low-dimensional representation of users and items based on users' ordinal preferences
 over items for visualization and fast retrieval of data.
- Supervisor: Assistant professor Hady W. Lauw.

FPT Technology Research Institute, **FPT Corporation**, Hanoi, Vietnam,

Position: Intern, part-time employee

Nov 2013 – May 2014

- **Project**: Statistical classification techniques for question reformulation problem.
- Description: Develop the "question reformulation" component for the FPT Question-Answering system, using statistical classification techniques and similarity measurements.

Mathematics Research Department, Company of Software Engineering, Hanoi, Vietnam,

Position: Intern, part-time employee

Aug 2012 – Sep 2013

- Project: Motorcycle detection, Error Correcting Codes for GSM
 - **Description**: 1) Use OpenCV library to build the system to recognize motorcycle from traffic videos. 2) Build the coding and decoding channel modules for GSM system, using theory of Error Correcting Codes.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

AY2019/20-Term 1: Graduate Instructor for IS103 Computational Thinking

AY2017/18-Term 2: Teaching Assistant for IS302 Information Security and Trust

AY2017/18-Term 1: Teaching Assistant for IS103 Computational Thinking

SERVICES

- [1] Program Committee:
 - 2020: PAKDD, IJCAI
- [2] External Reviewer:
 - 2017: PAKDD, DSAA
 - 2016: PAKDD, DSAA
- [13 Conference Assistant, IEEE International Conference on Data Mining 2018 (ICDM'18), December 2018.
- [4] Conference Volunteer, IEEE/WIC/ACM International Conference on Web Intelligence Intelligent Agent Technology 2015 (WI-IAT'15), December 2015.

LANGUAGES

Vietnamese (native language).

English.

SKILLS

Programming Language: MATLAB, R, Java, Python, C/C++.

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, Mac OS.

Framework: TensorFlow, PyTorch.

REFERENCES Hady W. Lauw,

Associate Professor of Information Systems, Singapore Management University, 80 Stamford Road, Singapore 178902, hadywlauw@smu.edu.sg • (+65) 6808-5277.

Baihua Zheng,

Professor of Information Systems, Singapore Management University, 80 Stamford Road, Singapore 178902, bhzheng@smu.edu.sg • (+65) 6828-0915.

Yuan FANG,

Assistant Professor of Information Systems, Singapore Management University, 80 Stamford Road, Singapore 178902, yfang@smu.edu.sg • (+65) 6808-5150.

Leong, Tze Yun,

Professor of Computer Science, School of Computing, National University of Singapore Computing I, 13 Computing Drive, Singapore 117417 leongty@comp.nus.edu.sg • (+65) 6516-6519.